<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"><channel><title>The Old School</title><description>Old School is the nuschool</description><link>https://ayal.github.io/oldschool/</link><item><title>10 Funniest Reactions To Facebook New Reactions</title><link>https://ayal.github.io/blog/10-funniest-reactions-facebook-new-reactions/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://ayal.github.io/blog/10-funniest-reactions-facebook-new-reactions/</guid><description>So Facebook decided to add new emoticons to the good ol&amp;#8217; Like button. They call them Reactions. Oh well, I guess in a world where Mark Zuckerberg can make smart people wear funny things on their head and think they are in the &amp;#8220;future&amp;#8221; &amp;#8211; a bunch of emoticons can be called &amp;#8220;reactions&amp;#8221;. Anyhoo&amp;#8230; Here are the funniest reactions to the [&amp;hellip;]</description><pubDate>Tue, 23 Feb 2016 22:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>3 Questions to Ask Yourself (and Your Client) Before Writing Copy</title><link>https://ayal.github.io/blog/3-questions-to-ask-before-writing-copy/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://ayal.github.io/blog/3-questions-to-ask-before-writing-copy/</guid><description>One of the toughest parts of writing copy &amp;#8211; and writing in general &amp;#8211; is firing up the engines. We’ve already covered how to begin writing and getting words from your head onto the page, so this time let’s go back to one step earlier &amp;#8211; how to even know what it is you’re supposed [&amp;hellip;]</description><pubDate>Sun, 24 May 2015 21:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>5 Google Tips for Creative Professionals</title><link>https://ayal.github.io/blog/5-google-tips-for-creative-professionals/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://ayal.github.io/blog/5-google-tips-for-creative-professionals/</guid><description>Google is my best friend. I ask it everything about anything. It responds quickly, relevantly and accurately to my questions. It is my one-stop-shop for knowledge, learning and problem-solving. It can help me a great deal with my personal life, with my hobbies or house-work. Even more so, as a freelancer working from home, communicating [&amp;hellip;]</description><pubDate>Mon, 02 Mar 2015 22:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>4 Mistakes To Avoid On The First Call With The Client [Video]</title><link>https://ayal.github.io/blog/4-mistakes-avoid-first-call-client-video/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://ayal.github.io/blog/4-mistakes-avoid-first-call-client-video/</guid><description>Do you tend to freak out when you a get a call from a new client? I used to as well, and then I learned some tricks that work like magic.  So here are classic mistakes that happen to everyone on the first call, and how you can avoid them. It&amp;#8217;s simple. &amp;nbsp; Some people prefer [&amp;hellip;]</description><pubDate>Sun, 14 Sep 2014 21:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>5 Ways To Increase Your Value To Your Client</title><link>https://ayal.github.io/blog/5-ways-to-increase-your-value-to-your-client/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://ayal.github.io/blog/5-ways-to-increase-your-value-to-your-client/</guid><description>Most of us, designers, assume our client cares only about the quality of our design work. While it&amp;#8217;s true that he cares how awesome our design is, the client also cares about other things. Here are 5 things your client cares about, and how to increase your value to him. Nail these, and you&amp;#8217;ll be able to charge more for your work.</description><pubDate>Sun, 26 Oct 2014 22:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>All Designers are Liars</title><link>https://ayal.github.io/blog/all-designers-are-liars-how-to-market-yourself/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://ayal.github.io/blog/all-designers-are-liars-how-to-market-yourself/</guid><description>Wait, hold on. Before you come after me for being intentionally provocative with my title, and before you jump to explain that you specifically are not a liar (“not all designers!”), let me explain what I’m talking about. My title is a reference to Seth Godin’s book, All Marketers are Liars. Seth doesn’t mean to [&amp;hellip;]</description><pubDate>Sun, 14 Jun 2015 21:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>BEHIND THE SCENES OF A PRODUCT LAUNCH</title><link>https://ayal.github.io/blog/behind-the-scenes-of-a-product-launch/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://ayal.github.io/blog/behind-the-scenes-of-a-product-launch/</guid><description>I’d like to take you with me for a journey. A journey I went through, on one of the most important days for me this year. The day where we’ve launched our new product – Prospero. We believe in full transperancy, so I have no problem to tell you how it went, including the numbers, …</description><pubDate>Tue, 07 Mar 2017 22:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Blogging For The Non-Blogger</title><link>https://ayal.github.io/blog/blogging-non-blogger/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://ayal.github.io/blog/blogging-non-blogger/</guid><description>20I&amp;#8217;m not a writer! Blogging is lame! I don&amp;#8217;t have anything to say! It&amp;#8217;s 2017, folks. The Internet is getting fuller every day. The only way to get out there is to&amp;#8230;get out there. And the time is now. Whether you&amp;#8217;re a natural writing talent or not, blogging doesn&amp;#8217;t have to be time-consuming or otherwise [&amp;hellip;]</description><pubDate>Mon, 27 Mar 2017 21:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Bilingual Freelance? Watch Your Language!</title><link>https://ayal.github.io/blog/bilingual-freelance-watch-language/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://ayal.github.io/blog/bilingual-freelance-watch-language/</guid><description>Editor’s note: This guest post is written by Jonathan Maimon. He is a bilingual freelance copywriter and internet marketer, working with a bunch of brands, as well as creating new media for Kinetis. Jonathan has spent the recent years between NY, London and Tel-Aviv. In the very little spare time he has left, Jonathan delves into music production, as can be heard on [&amp;hellip;]</description><pubDate>Mon, 27 Oct 2014 22:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Be a Better Freelance Designer</title><link>https://ayal.github.io/blog/better-freelance-designer/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://ayal.github.io/blog/better-freelance-designer/</guid><description>Here are the lessons I’ve learned that will aid you in the years to come to be a better freelance designer. 1. Work when you are at your most creative Don’t just sit there and stress about it, get up, move around, watch TV and do everything you can to switch off from the design challenges [&amp;hellip;]</description><pubDate>Wed, 21 Jan 2015 22:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>The clients misses deadlines - nuANSWERS</title><link>https://ayal.github.io/blog/client-deadlines-how-to-make-them-respect-it-ask-the-nuschool/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://ayal.github.io/blog/client-deadlines-how-to-make-them-respect-it-ask-the-nuschool/</guid><description>“nuANSWERS” is where we feature an actual question submitted by one of our students and the answer we gave them. This week’s question comes from KT, who wants her clients to stop being late with providing her with what she needs to complete the work. KT wrote: Dear Lior, I have a question. I often write [&amp;hellip;]</description><pubDate>Mon, 23 Feb 2015 22:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>How A Videographer + Motion Designer Used The nuSchool To Create A Career</title><link>https://ayal.github.io/blog/case-study-sivan/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://ayal.github.io/blog/case-study-sivan/</guid><description>The first time we met, Sivan had a glowing grin. She was carrying two overstuffed XL bags of brand new camera equipment, in preparation for a full day shooting promo videos for a local education startup. A year before, this was a dream &amp;#8212; the equipment, the client, all of the clients. But, with some [&amp;hellip;]</description><pubDate>Sat, 07 May 2016 21:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>A Brand Designer, A Pricing Problem, And The nuSchool</title><link>https://ayal.github.io/blog/case-study-zee/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://ayal.github.io/blog/case-study-zee/</guid><description>Do you have anyone whose messages immediately make you smile? For me, that&amp;#8217;s Zee Cornelius. Zee is a brand designer whom I&amp;#8217;ve had the privilege of meeting through The nuSchool community. She&amp;#8217;s an absolute joy, beaming positivity and light &amp;#8212; so when she told me how much of that career happiness she and her husband [&amp;hellip;]</description><pubDate>Sun, 12 Jun 2016 21:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>These Client Stories Will Make You Cry With Laughter</title><link>https://ayal.github.io/blog/client-stories-will-make-cry-laughter/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://ayal.github.io/blog/client-stories-will-make-cry-laughter/</guid><description>Nigntmare clients. I didn&amp;#8217;t sign up for that when I decided to be a creative freelancer. But I guess it comes with the job. In realtime, clients can make me cry. In retrospect &amp;#8211; they make me cry with laugher. ClientsFromHell is a super-duper-funny website that is curating stories about&amp;#8230; well you guessed it &amp;#8211; about [&amp;hellip;]</description><pubDate>Sun, 03 Aug 2014 21:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Can designers beat Fiverr and 99Designs?</title><link>https://ayal.github.io/blog/can-designers-beat-low-price-competitors/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://ayal.github.io/blog/can-designers-beat-low-price-competitors/</guid><description>One of our biggest fears is that our clients will find out someone else who would be willing to do the same work, but for a lower price. The fear is then swiftly replaced by anger: “Aren’t those designers ashamed of themselves? They’re destroying the market!”. We end up trying to educate our clients that if they [&amp;hellip;]</description><pubDate>Tue, 02 Dec 2014 22:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Don&apos;t Fear The Clients</title><link>https://ayal.github.io/blog/clients-friends-not-food/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://ayal.github.io/blog/clients-friends-not-food/</guid><description>If you&amp;#8217;re into children&amp;#8217;s animated movies (like I am) you might have seen the movie Finding Nemo, which is about a little clownfish that gets lost and goes on a wild adventure. In the movie, Nemo&amp;#8217;s dad sets out into the huge ocean, away from the safety of their anemone, to find his son. Along [&amp;hellip;]</description><pubDate>Sun, 03 Apr 2016 21:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Your Client Wants You To Charge Less. Don&apos;t.</title><link>https://ayal.github.io/blog/clients-get-charge-less-shouldnt/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://ayal.github.io/blog/clients-get-charge-less-shouldnt/</guid><description>Have you ever walked down the street and heard a stranger whisper to you from a dark alley, “Hey, come here! I have some really low-paying design work to offer you! It’ll make you famous! You can trust me!” So many of us step into those dark alleys again and again because those sketchy strangers in [&amp;hellip;]</description><pubDate>Mon, 29 Feb 2016 22:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Clients Want the Solution, Not the Service</title><link>https://ayal.github.io/blog/clients-want-solution-not-service/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://ayal.github.io/blog/clients-want-solution-not-service/</guid><description>I had never been so terrified in my life. There I was, at one of the busiest intersections in downtown Norfolk, Virginia, and my car wouldn&amp;#8217;t start. In the middle of the intersection. On a green light. Trying to turn left. This was sphincter-clenching-I&amp;#8217;m-about-to-get-hit-by-three-different-cars-and-ohmygod-is-that-a-semi-truck type of panic. My car had died again and no one [&amp;hellip;]</description><pubDate>Sun, 10 Jan 2016 22:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Clients Don&amp;#8217;t Care How You Do Your Work</title><link>https://ayal.github.io/blog/clients-dont-care-how-you-do-your-work/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://ayal.github.io/blog/clients-dont-care-how-you-do-your-work/</guid><description>You&amp;#8217;re really good at what you do, you&amp;#8217;re really talented, and you&amp;#8217;ve got a great portfolio, so why aren&amp;#8217;t new clients beating down your door? Many times, when we&amp;#8217;re on an initial call with a client, we jump right in to telling the client about the features of our services instead of the benefits we [&amp;hellip;]</description><pubDate>Tue, 01 Dec 2015 22:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Can designers steal the best pricing techniques from restaurants?</title><link>https://ayal.github.io/blog/can-steal-restaurants-best-pricing-techniques/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://ayal.github.io/blog/can-steal-restaurants-best-pricing-techniques/</guid><description>You can learn a few awesome pricing techniques just by looking at how menus are designed. When I look at restaurant menus, my brain divides into two. The primitive part, which makes salivate at the food. At the same time, there is the analytical part, which tries to work out whether or not I’m subjected to pricing [&amp;hellip;]</description><pubDate>Mon, 24 Nov 2014 22:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Agenda For Your Kickass Freelance Creative Career [Infographic]</title><link>https://ayal.github.io/blog/creative-freelance-career-agenda/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://ayal.github.io/blog/creative-freelance-career-agenda/</guid><description>Wait, what? Agenda? What are you &amp;#8211; a politician? Nope. I&amp;#8217;m a creative freelancer. But I believe I need an agenda behind what I do and how I do things. An agenda that will help me &amp;#8211; and maybe you too &amp;#8211; to build a long-lasting career that they&amp;#8217;re happy with. [I created an Infographic so you can print it [&amp;hellip;]</description><pubDate>Mon, 20 Feb 2017 22:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>How to deal with creative block</title><link>https://ayal.github.io/blog/creative-block/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://ayal.github.io/blog/creative-block/</guid><description>My heart is pounding. Suddenly cleaning up the house seems like a fun task. Maybe I should take the trash out too? Anything that will keep me from sitting down in front of the computer and facing the fact I have no idea what to do. No matter how many years I’ve been doing it, [&amp;hellip;]</description><pubDate>Sun, 01 Feb 2015 22:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Freelance Creative Professionals Protection Act: What you need to know</title><link>https://ayal.github.io/blog/creative-professionals-protection-act-need-know/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://ayal.github.io/blog/creative-professionals-protection-act-need-know/</guid><description>In a few weeks, during April 2015, President Obama and the US Congress will meet to discuss the Freelance Creative Professionals Protection Act, whose purpose is to better define the work being done by creatives &amp;#8211; designers, writers, video editors and so on &amp;#8211; in relation to their clients. Should everything go smoothly, the FCPP Act [&amp;hellip;]</description><pubDate>Tue, 31 Mar 2015 21:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Creatives Need Hobbies. Here&amp;#8217;s Why.</title><link>https://ayal.github.io/blog/creatives-need-hobbies/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://ayal.github.io/blog/creatives-need-hobbies/</guid><description>When you&amp;#8217;re a freelance creative, chances are, your job is doing what you love. Congratulations! You still need to love doing something else. Doing what you love every day is a great privilege. And, chances are, you earned that! But, as is the nature of the world, anything you do for money eventually becomes work. And then [&amp;hellip;]</description><pubDate>Mon, 01 Aug 2016 21:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Create your WordPress website without coding in 15 minutes</title><link>https://ayal.github.io/blog/create-a-wordpress-website-just-15-min-no-coding-needed/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://ayal.github.io/blog/create-a-wordpress-website-just-15-min-no-coding-needed/</guid><description>Setting up a WordPress website is becoming more and more like opening a Facebook account; but people still fear this process, and find it more difficult than it actually is. But fear not! I’m going to show you how to create a WordPress website in 15 minutes! Without having to know how to code. Many designers [&amp;hellip;]</description><pubDate>Sun, 22 Feb 2015 22:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Designer Resolutions: What 2015 Was, What 2016 Will Be</title><link>https://ayal.github.io/blog/designer-resolutions-2016/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://ayal.github.io/blog/designer-resolutions-2016/</guid><description>New Year&amp;#8217;s is cleansing. It&amp;#8217;s a chance to step back from the year you&amp;#8217;ve had and figure out what you want to change &amp;#8212; what you promise yourself you&amp;#8217;ll make better, or different. Reflecting ain&amp;#8217;t easy, so we&amp;#8217;ve called up some of our favorite designers to tell us about the year they&amp;#8217;ve had and what they want [&amp;hellip;]</description><pubDate>Sun, 03 Jan 2016 22:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Why Design Students Should Freelance</title><link>https://ayal.github.io/blog/design-students-freelance/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://ayal.github.io/blog/design-students-freelance/</guid><description>One of the most valuable things I learned fairly early in my college career was the importance of freelancing as a design student. The value of this became more obvious every year until I graduated by seeing the work done by students who freelanced versus students who did no more work than they were assigned [&amp;hellip;]</description><pubDate>Mon, 09 Feb 2015 22:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Creative Hangover Solutions For New Year&amp;#8217;s</title><link>https://ayal.github.io/blog/creative-hangover-solutions-new-years/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://ayal.github.io/blog/creative-hangover-solutions-new-years/</guid><description>We’re heading into a new cycle around the sun, and while that should sound exciting, what it really means is that&amp;#8230; Tomorrow is going to hurt! New Year’s Eve is a night of champagne, confetti, and you-should-definitely-take-a-taxi &amp;#8212; and New Year’s Day is a shitstorm of a hangover. But what if it didn’t have to [&amp;hellip;]</description><pubDate>Wed, 30 Dec 2015 22:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>A Designer&amp;#8217;s Sales Philosophy</title><link>https://ayal.github.io/blog/designers-sales-philosophy/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://ayal.github.io/blog/designers-sales-philosophy/</guid><description>I don&amp;#8217;t like being sold to. All of those advertisements that say, buy me, buy me &amp;#8212; that&amp;#8217;s gross. It&amp;#8217;s not how I like to be informed about a product, and it&amp;#8217;s definitely not how I want to sell my services to future clients. To watch me talk about this on video, press play &amp;#8212; I start [&amp;hellip;]</description><pubDate>Sat, 21 May 2016 21:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Leading Designers Share Their New Year&amp;#8217;s Resolutions for 2015</title><link>https://ayal.github.io/blog/designers-new-years-resolutions-2015/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://ayal.github.io/blog/designers-new-years-resolutions-2015/</guid><description>The holidays offer us the chance to relax and rethink what we wish for ourselves for the next year. But starting with a blank page is hard, so we thought you might want to hear what other designers wish for themselves. We asked a number of our favourite super-talented, uber-awesome designers &amp;#8220;What is your new year&amp;#8217;s resolution?&amp;#8221; Their answers were inspiring, thoughtful and hilarious at times. [&amp;hellip;]</description><pubDate>Mon, 29 Dec 2014 22:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Escaping The &amp;#8216;Yes&amp;#8217; Cycle</title><link>https://ayal.github.io/blog/escaping-the-yes-cycle/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://ayal.github.io/blog/escaping-the-yes-cycle/</guid><description>Have you ever been bullied into taking a project? A few years ago, after a pretty tough few months, I took a project with a design agency. The agency had offered me a full-time position a few months earlier, but I stuck to my freelance guns. When they couldn&amp;#8217;t find someone they liked as much to [&amp;hellip;]</description><pubDate>Tue, 04 Apr 2017 21:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>How I eliminated fear from my negotiations</title><link>https://ayal.github.io/blog/eliminate-fear-negotiations-get-deserve/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://ayal.github.io/blog/eliminate-fear-negotiations-get-deserve/</guid><description>Most of us creative freelancers aren’t greedy. We just want to earn a decent living. So how come so many of us are afraid to state what we really want when we negotiate for our projects? See how to conduct negotiations to get what you deserve. We are afraid of losing a job to other designers who will [&amp;hellip;]</description><pubDate>Sun, 01 Mar 2015 22:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>How To Find A Creative Freelance Mentor</title><link>https://ayal.github.io/blog/find-a-mentor/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://ayal.github.io/blog/find-a-mentor/</guid><description>When you’re trying to build the independent career of your dreams, having a mentor to help you grow as a freelancer and achieve your goals is a no-brainer. Even if you’re confident in your creative skills and have no trouble finding clients, speaking with another experienced freelancer who’s been in your shoes before can help [&amp;hellip;]</description><pubDate>Sat, 20 May 2017 21:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>F*ck You, Pay Me!</title><link>https://ayal.github.io/blog/fck-you-pay-me/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://ayal.github.io/blog/fck-you-pay-me/</guid><description>My mom taught me not to curse. But some people are really asking for it. Say, customers that don’t pay for the design job you delivered, in which you put so much energy. You might feel like you wanna flip a table (╯°□°）╯︵ ┻━┻  but apparently there are better ways to handle it. Here’s a video we [&amp;hellip;]</description><pubDate>Mon, 25 Aug 2014 21:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>What Freelance Health Insurance Looks Like</title><link>https://ayal.github.io/blog/freelancers-health-insurance-guide/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://ayal.github.io/blog/freelancers-health-insurance-guide/</guid><description>Freelance life is pretty great, but there&amp;#8217;s one employee-life perk we haven&amp;#8217;t managed to get over: employer-sponsored health insurance. Bummer. This means you must purchase an individual health plan to protect against unexpected (and very expensive) medical bills, and to avoid paying a government fine ($695 in 2016 for individuals). Your health plan has to fit [&amp;hellip;]</description><pubDate>Wed, 09 Dec 2015 22:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>I Quit Freelancing</title><link>https://ayal.github.io/blog/freelancing-isnt-for-me/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://ayal.github.io/blog/freelancing-isnt-for-me/</guid><description>Easy come, easy go, right? I don&amp;#8217;t remember ever deciding to be a freelance writer. I don&amp;#8217;t think I gave it much thought. Over the course of six months I moved across the world (from New York to Tel Aviv), moved apartments three times, learned a new language, made a new group of friends, and [&amp;hellip;]</description><pubDate>Mon, 22 Aug 2016 21:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Freelancing With Depression: The Real Story</title><link>https://ayal.github.io/blog/freelancing-with-depression/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://ayal.github.io/blog/freelancing-with-depression/</guid><description>In honor of Mental Health Awareness Week, I&amp;#8217;m sharing my story &amp;#8212; the behind-the-scenes life of a full-time freelancer struggling with depression, anxiety, and not losing my shit. Anyone who knows me pretty well would tell you I&amp;#8217;m a happy person. Anyone who knows me really well knows I&amp;#8217;m not. My narrative is punctuated with depressive episodes [&amp;hellip;]</description><pubDate>Mon, 16 May 2016 21:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Don&apos;t Try To Be Everyone&apos;s Flavor (What I Learned From Pasta)</title><link>https://ayal.github.io/blog/dont-try-everyones-flavor-proven-pasta/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://ayal.github.io/blog/dont-try-everyones-flavor-proven-pasta/</guid><description>If I say Italy, what do you think of? Right, pizza. But some of you have better taste than me, and you might have something else come to mind: Pasta. And where is pasta most popular in the world? Italy! Nah&amp;#8230; just kidding. It&amp;#8217;s the USA. And where there&amp;#8217;s tons of pasta, there are dozens of flavors of pasta [&amp;hellip;]</description><pubDate>Sun, 20 Dec 2015 22:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>The Badass List of Free Stock Photos Websites for Designers</title><link>https://ayal.github.io/blog/free-stock-photos-websites-awesome-list/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://ayal.github.io/blog/free-stock-photos-websites-awesome-list/</guid><description>All the stock photos you can eat. Galleries, tools and websites you shouldn&amp;#8217;t miss. Why is it so freaking hard to find high quality, high-res free stock photos with no watermarks or shitty-designed websites around them? Show me the list Show me the tools I mean, great photographers should get paid for their awesome work. But the [&amp;hellip;]</description><pubDate>Tue, 24 Mar 2015 22:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Six Weeks From Broke To Fully-Booked</title><link>https://ayal.github.io/blog/fully-booked-six-weeks-journey-broke-land/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://ayal.github.io/blog/fully-booked-six-weeks-journey-broke-land/</guid><description>&amp;nbsp; What do you do when you realize you don’t know what you’re doing? An email from a potential client asking for a price quote sent me over the edge. I’m a creative. Money is good enough. Just pay me money. That was when I realized I had a big problem. I was getting paid [&amp;hellip;]</description><pubDate>Sun, 27 Dec 2015 22:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Get Paid What You&amp;#8217;re Worth Q&amp;#038;A</title><link>https://ayal.github.io/blog/get-paid-youre-worth-qa/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://ayal.github.io/blog/get-paid-youre-worth-qa/</guid><description>In May, The nuSchool had a webinar called Getting Paid What You&amp;#8217;re Worth. Because isn&amp;#8217;t that what freelancing is all about? These are some of the questions I was asked after the webinar. I promised to share my answers &amp;#8212; so here they are. Enjoy them. Q: Can you charge more for an urgent or last minute [&amp;hellip;]</description><pubDate>Tue, 14 Jun 2016 21:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>How To Get Started As A Freelance Graphic Designer</title><link>https://ayal.github.io/blog/get-started-freelance-graphic-designer/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://ayal.github.io/blog/get-started-freelance-graphic-designer/</guid><description>Have you ever wondered what it takes to get started out as a freelance graphic designer? If you are thinking about venturing into the field of graphic design for yourself, then this article should prove to help you tremendously! I will be giving you a look at how I got started out in the freelancing [&amp;hellip;]</description><pubDate>Wed, 18 Feb 2015 22:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Getting Everything Done Without Going Crazy: Here&amp;#8217;s How</title><link>https://ayal.github.io/blog/getting-everything-done/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://ayal.github.io/blog/getting-everything-done/</guid><description>Keeping your head straight ain&amp;#8217;t easy. When you&amp;#8217;re a freelancer, you have a lot to keep straight. From making breakfast to making payments, the lines between personal and business can blur reeeeal fast, and things can get messy. Getting overwhelmed is a problem because overwhelmed people tend towards two bad traits: forgetfulness and impulsiveness. So, here&amp;#8217;s some information [&amp;hellip;]</description><pubDate>Mon, 18 Jul 2016 21:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Freelance Life &amp;#8211; Get Through It With This Video Channel</title><link>https://ayal.github.io/blog/get-through-freelance-life-with-videos/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://ayal.github.io/blog/get-through-freelance-life-with-videos/</guid><description>&amp;#8220;It&amp;#8217;s the era of Video&amp;#8221; &amp;#8211; said Ran, my co-founder that runs a cool Vlog &amp;#8211; &amp;#8220;Let&amp;#8217;s talk Freelance Life through videos!&amp;#8221; It took me a while to listen to him. Not because I think he&amp;#8217;s stupid &amp;#8211; because I was afraid. I was afraid of video editing &amp;#8211; a skill that I just don&amp;#8217;t have. Until now. At [&amp;hellip;]</description><pubDate>Tue, 12 Jul 2016 21:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Getting Paid As A Freelance Designer</title><link>https://ayal.github.io/blog/getting-paid-as-a-freelancer/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://ayal.github.io/blog/getting-paid-as-a-freelancer/</guid><description>As a freelancer, or small business owner, it&amp;#8217;s extremely important to get paid as soon as possible because more than likely you don&amp;#8217;t have a Scrooge McDuck money bin to help you out. Money can be a tricky subject, and for one reason or another getting paid as a freelancer on time is something that [&amp;hellip;]</description><pubDate>Sun, 17 May 2015 21:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Have a fresh start in 2015: Accomplish those things during the holidays</title><link>https://ayal.github.io/blog/got-holiday-boredom-10-dos-will-guarantee-fresh-start-2015/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://ayal.github.io/blog/got-holiday-boredom-10-dos-will-guarantee-fresh-start-2015/</guid><description>The holidays are coming and everyone’s on vacation. Your email inbox is as dry as the Sahara and every other message you send out gets you an automated reply: “off to the Caribbeans for a month, back January 6th.” Meanwhile you are sitting in front of your computer with a couple of hours to kill and [&amp;hellip;]</description><pubDate>Sun, 21 Dec 2014 22:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>A Creative&apos;s Guide To Taking Criticism</title><link>https://ayal.github.io/blog/graceully-handling-criticism/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://ayal.github.io/blog/graceully-handling-criticism/</guid><description>Freelancing can be a real pain in the balls. Or the lady balls, in my case. You had this shiny idea in your head of how it was going to go. You wake up every morning in your California king sized bed. You swagger over to your window and look out from your penthouse apartment [&amp;hellip;]</description><pubDate>Mon, 15 Aug 2016 21:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>How a Graphic Designer Used the Pricing Class to Raise Her Rates</title><link>https://ayal.github.io/blog/how-a-graphic-designer-used-the-pricing-class-to-raise-her-rates/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://ayal.github.io/blog/how-a-graphic-designer-used-the-pricing-class-to-raise-her-rates/</guid><description>“She got the project!” I screamed at my girlfriend. “I knew it!” “Who? What?” My other half had no clue what I’m talking about. “Margot! Our student &amp;#8211; the French designer from London. She’s going to create an amazing brand for her client, and she got it in the price she wanted!” My girlfriend wasn’t [&amp;hellip;]</description><pubDate>Mon, 15 Jun 2015 21:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>How a Web Designer Used the Pricing Class to Create an Outstanding Proposal</title><link>https://ayal.github.io/blog/how-a-web-designer-used-the-pricing-class-to-create-an-outstanding-proposal/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://ayal.github.io/blog/how-a-web-designer-used-the-pricing-class-to-create-an-outstanding-proposal/</guid><description>&amp;#8220;I took Lior&amp;#8217;s advice and created a proposal as a webpage, instead of sending a boring old PDF. The reaction was &amp;#8220;Wow!&amp;#8221;&amp;#8221; This is the story of Tara Hoover &amp;#8211; a web designer who started freelancing only a few months ago &amp;#8211; and is already mastering the way to write proposals and win projects.  I asked her [&amp;hellip;]</description><pubDate>Sun, 21 Jun 2015 21:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>How Designers are Profiting from Ecommerce</title><link>https://ayal.github.io/blog/how-designers-are-profiting-from-ecommerce/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://ayal.github.io/blog/how-designers-are-profiting-from-ecommerce/</guid><description>Let’s be honest : being a freelance designer or web professional is a mixture of extreme highs and devastating lows. For all the freedom it offers — for all the great and varied projects you get to work on— we’ve all experienced empty calendars and periods of self doubt. I’ve had two large freelance spells [&amp;hellip;]</description><pubDate>Sun, 26 Jul 2015 21:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>&amp;#8220;How Much Should I Charge?&amp;#8221;</title><link>https://ayal.github.io/blog/how-much-should-i-charge/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://ayal.github.io/blog/how-much-should-i-charge/</guid><description>How many times did you ask yourself this question? A potential client wants your proposal for a design project. You&amp;#8217;re sitting in front of your computer, scratching your head. You ask Google, your friends in Facebook, your Linkedin groups. You browse designers&amp;#8217; forums. You&amp;#8217;ve found some price lists. Are they relevant for you? Are they relevant for this [&amp;hellip;]</description><pubDate>Tue, 07 Oct 2014 21:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>How to Get Over Your Fear of Failing at a Job You Love</title><link>https://ayal.github.io/blog/how-to-get-over-fear/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://ayal.github.io/blog/how-to-get-over-fear/</guid><description>It was 1 a.m. and I was still writing headlines over and over, sitting in bed, my hair a mess and my tea long gone. I&amp;#8217;d promised that I would finish this tonight, and I (wrongly) assumed that I could magically work faster on a tight deadline. So of course I&amp;#8217;d left myself only a [&amp;hellip;]</description><pubDate>Mon, 22 Feb 2016 22:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><link>https://ayal.github.io/blog/how-to-build-confidence-when-you-start-freelancing/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://ayal.github.io/blog/how-to-build-confidence-when-you-start-freelancing/</guid><description>How do you start freelancing? It’s easy. Learn your profession, find those clients and charge them for that service! There is a slight chance you’ll face some obstacles. One of them is really tiny, not too big of a deal.. It is the fact that it is FREAKING SCARY. The number one issue I have [&amp;hellip;]</description><pubDate>Mon, 29 Feb 2016 22:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>How To Get Your Focus Back. Your Time Too.</title><link>https://ayal.github.io/blog/how-to-get-your-focus-back-your-mind-too/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://ayal.github.io/blog/how-to-get-your-focus-back-your-mind-too/</guid><description>We are freelancers. We need to manage our time, our projects, to be our own chief financial officer, customer manager, the marketing guy and.. oh right&amp;#8230; we also need to work for what we were hired for &amp;#8211; to be creative. On top of all that we&amp;#8217;ve got to do every day, our technological body [&amp;hellip;]</description><pubDate>Tue, 26 Aug 2014 21:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>It’s Not Talent, It’s Willpower</title><link>https://ayal.github.io/blog/how-to-increase-your-willpower/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://ayal.github.io/blog/how-to-increase-your-willpower/</guid><description>Albert Einstein famously said that genius is 1% talent and 99% hard work. That’s probably true, but I’ve noticed something else about hard work: first of all, it’s not easy to do. Secondly, most people try to avoid hard work at all cost, even the talented ones. The thing about doing difficult things is that [&amp;hellip;]</description><pubDate>Tue, 04 Aug 2015 21:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>How I got unexpected money for a design job [case study]</title><link>https://ayal.github.io/blog/how-to-get-unexpected-money-case-study/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://ayal.github.io/blog/how-to-get-unexpected-money-case-study/</guid><description>Today I’m going to share with you my best strategies for getting unexpected money from my clients, based on a real-life example. Why do I call it unexpected money? Well, because it’s money my clients weren’t planning on investing in the first place. Also because it’s a catchy title. I promise that I didn’t drag you here [&amp;hellip;]</description><pubDate>Mon, 07 Sep 2015 21:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>How To Manage Yourself</title><link>https://ayal.github.io/blog/how-to-manage-yourself/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://ayal.github.io/blog/how-to-manage-yourself/</guid><description>Sometimes people tell me stuff like: “I can never be a freelancer, cuz I can’t manage myself” or “I can’t work from home, there’s just too many temptations” or maybe “I don’t have enough willpower to manage myself”. Somehow I’ve got the feeling people think that when you’re a freelancer you’ve got to be a [&amp;hellip;]</description><pubDate>Tue, 26 Aug 2014 21:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>How to Sell Without Selling</title><link>https://ayal.github.io/blog/how-to-sell-without-selling/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://ayal.github.io/blog/how-to-sell-without-selling/</guid><description>My girlfriend, Marisa, is a few months into her new career as a freelance copywriter and editor. She has a literature degree1 and hundreds of thousands of words under her belt. She’s written for large publications. She’s created an information product and the marketing to go with it. I’m telling you this to establish a [&amp;hellip;]</description><pubDate>Mon, 16 Nov 2015 22:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>How to take a vacation</title><link>https://ayal.github.io/blog/how-to-take-a-vacation/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://ayal.github.io/blog/how-to-take-a-vacation/</guid><description>Her: Want to go out for a day tomorrow? Let’s drive to a vinery and drink some good wine. Me: No way I can skip an entire day. I need to finish-up the design for the Cats Pajamas&amp;#8217; website, and I have to be available for my clients. The life of a freelancer&amp;#8230; Her: Hold on a minute, if you’re a [&amp;hellip;]</description><pubDate>Tue, 18 Nov 2014 22:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>I Need Clients. N-O-W.</title><link>https://ayal.github.io/blog/i-need-clients/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://ayal.github.io/blog/i-need-clients/</guid><description>&amp;#8220;Shayna, how do you find your clients?&amp;#8221; Every single freelancer I&amp;#8217;ve ever met, from the ones who just started to the big-league consultants, has, at some point, asked me that same question. That is, unless I beat them to it. While it&amp;#8217;s obvious, it&amp;#8217;s still kind of weird to say out loud that we&amp;#8217;re all looking for new [&amp;hellip;]</description><pubDate>Mon, 14 Nov 2016 22:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>How I&amp;#8217;m going to make 2015 more fun and more profitable</title><link>https://ayal.github.io/blog/im-going-make-2015-fun-profitable/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://ayal.github.io/blog/im-going-make-2015-fun-profitable/</guid><description>I’m going to tell you how five years ago I changed my own life course, and how my life has been getting better and better ever since. By the time you’re done reading this you will understand how to make 2015 a better year in terms of profit, fun, and in moving forward with your [&amp;hellip;]</description><pubDate>Wed, 14 Jan 2015 22:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Inspirational Videos For Designers &amp;#8211; The Big Collection</title><link>https://ayal.github.io/blog/inspirational-videos-for-designers-the-full-collection/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://ayal.github.io/blog/inspirational-videos-for-designers-the-full-collection/</guid><description>The biggest collection of inspirational videos for designers is here: TED videos for designers The Best of Creative Mornings You see, as much as I love full-length features, sometimes what you really want is just something quick to watch and get inspired by. I love seeing how amazing speakers are spreading their great thoughts, ideas and [&amp;hellip;]</description><pubDate>Wed, 24 Jun 2015 21:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Learn from bad clients</title><link>https://ayal.github.io/blog/learn-bad-clients/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://ayal.github.io/blog/learn-bad-clients/</guid><description>I want to write my experiences and lessons from a recent logo design project I took on, which unfortunately did not go as well as I would have hoped. I still have a good relationship with this client, and although a final design was selected and full payment was made, I am aware that unfortunately [&amp;hellip;]</description><pubDate>Sat, 21 Mar 2015 22:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Doing The Hard Things</title><link>https://ayal.github.io/blog/just-talking-hard-things/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://ayal.github.io/blog/just-talking-hard-things/</guid><description>The hardest thing about running your own creative business is [fill in the blank here]. Being a freelancer has this very romantic narrative of being your own boss. Making your own hours. Total creative freedom. But what about the hard parts? Maybe it is romantic in all of those ways and more, but we all [&amp;hellip;]</description><pubDate>Wed, 03 Feb 2016 22:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>How To Make A Living as a Creative Freelancer Within a Year</title><link>https://ayal.github.io/blog/make-living-creative-freelancer-within-year/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://ayal.github.io/blog/make-living-creative-freelancer-within-year/</guid><description>I am only 21. A young age to give advice &amp;#8211; I know &amp;#8211; but still, I want to share with you my little experience. Because I got to what I thought was impossible. Within a single year of being a freelance designer &amp;#8211; I can make a living. And I thought you might want to [&amp;hellip;]</description><pubDate>Mon, 30 Jan 2017 22:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Honest Marketing For Creatives 101</title><link>https://ayal.github.io/blog/marketing-creatives-101/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://ayal.github.io/blog/marketing-creatives-101/</guid><description>Marketing is the business way of saying make people like you enough to buy your product/hire you/give you money. When you&amp;#8217;re a freelance creative, talent doesn&amp;#8217;t sell itself. To have clients, your clients have to know you exist &amp;#8212; so you have to do a bit of marketing. The highest-paid freelancers figured this out a long [&amp;hellip;]</description><pubDate>Mon, 01 Feb 2016 22:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>The loneliness of the freelance designer</title><link>https://ayal.github.io/blog/loneliness-freelance-designer/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://ayal.github.io/blog/loneliness-freelance-designer/</guid><description>When I was 23 I experimented with loneliness &amp;#8211; I used to read a lot of Paul Auster at the time, and I wanted to see what would happen if I am really alone and avoid talking to other people for a while. So I rented an apartment in a small fishing village in the [&amp;hellip;]</description><pubDate>Tue, 03 Mar 2015 22:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>How I Found My First Paying Client</title><link>https://ayal.github.io/blog/journey-finding-first-client/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://ayal.github.io/blog/journey-finding-first-client/</guid><description>Where can a single young freelancer find a handsome client with a decent budget to pay her for a design? It’s a tough world out there. Online dating sites are just terrible. So are those massive online job-hunting platforms. They give us the illusion that there are tons of options out there for us. I’m not saying [&amp;hellip;]</description><pubDate>Tue, 17 Mar 2015 22:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Marketing For Honest Creatives &amp;#8211; Free Ebook</title><link>https://ayal.github.io/blog/marketing-honest-freelancers-free-ebook/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://ayal.github.io/blog/marketing-honest-freelancers-free-ebook/</guid><description>‘Marketing’ is the business way of saying making people like you enough to buy your product/hire you/give you money. When you’re a freelance creative, talent doesn’t sell itself. To have clients, your clients have to know you exist — so you have to do a bit of marketing. The highest-paid freelancers figured this out a [&amp;hellip;]</description><pubDate>Sun, 30 Oct 2016 22:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Common Freelance Mistakes</title><link>https://ayal.github.io/blog/mistakes-freelancers-make/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://ayal.github.io/blog/mistakes-freelancers-make/</guid><description>I want to share with you the biggest mistake I think I made starting out as a freelance designer. I didn’t correctly position myself in the market. Based on the inquiries that I get every week, I’m going to bet that you too are making the same mistake. It’s okay, there are mistakes freelancers make. I’m [&amp;hellip;]</description><pubDate>Tue, 12 May 2015 21:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Most Clients Are Dead</title><link>https://ayal.github.io/blog/most-clients-are-dead/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://ayal.github.io/blog/most-clients-are-dead/</guid><description>“My target audience is everybody.” Have you ever heard someone say that? This week I met an entrepreneur in the the wellness niche who was angry that she couldn’t find a designer that “got” her. “I ask them for a logo, and they make something purple. Don’t they get that wellness isn’t just for women?! [&amp;hellip;]</description><pubDate>Tue, 19 Jan 2016 22:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>MY BEST WRITING TIP [VIDEO]</title><link>https://ayal.github.io/blog/my-best-writing-tip-video/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://ayal.github.io/blog/my-best-writing-tip-video/</guid><description>“You should fart more”. This is how my book (it’s in Hebrew) starts. Ran Segall, my partner at The nuSchool, has a super awesome Youtube channel called Flux. He asked me if I’m willing to answer a question for him. I wasn’t ready for it. He surprised me. He asked me to give him writing &amp;#8230;</description><pubDate>Sun, 07 May 2017 21:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Nailing The Face-To-Face Meeting</title><link>https://ayal.github.io/blog/nailing-the-face-to-face-meeting/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://ayal.github.io/blog/nailing-the-face-to-face-meeting/</guid><description>&amp;nbsp; Profuse sweating? Check. Mysterious stain on my shirt? Check. One solitary hair that refuses to be slicked down? Check. Sounds like I&amp;#8217;m meeting a client for coffee. Cue the anxiety. &amp;#8212; It&amp;#8217;s easy to forget who your client really is. When your only communication is email and *maybe* the occasional phone call, the client [&amp;hellip;]</description><pubDate>Mon, 19 Sep 2016 21:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Muzli &amp;#8211; Designers&amp;#8217; Secret Source</title><link>https://ayal.github.io/blog/muzli-designers-secret-source/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://ayal.github.io/blog/muzli-designers-secret-source/</guid><pubDate>Tue, 08 Dec 2015 22:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>NEVER GIVE UP? REALLY?</title><link>https://ayal.github.io/blog/never-give-up-really/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://ayal.github.io/blog/never-give-up-really/</guid><description>It&amp;#8217;s a matter of what you give up on, and what you&amp;#8217;re not.</description><pubDate>Sun, 07 Aug 2016 21:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>My client hurt my feelings</title><link>https://ayal.github.io/blog/my-client-hurt-my-feelings/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://ayal.github.io/blog/my-client-hurt-my-feelings/</guid><description>It happened more than once, and I want to share with you how I deal with it. Some clients&amp;#8230; well it doesn’t matter how fair I am with them, or how much I do my best to make them happy &amp;#8211; some clients can be **sholes! I know, I should be professional. I know, I [&amp;hellip;]</description><pubDate>Sun, 19 Jul 2015 21:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Networking Doesn&apos;t Have To Suck (Here&apos;s How)</title><link>https://ayal.github.io/blog/networking-for-creatives/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://ayal.github.io/blog/networking-for-creatives/</guid><description>Did you finish design school fully booked? I didn’t. I freelanced through school, between jobs, and in the evenings, building my portfolio, my network, and my savings account. Getting to be a full-time freelancer took a few &amp;#8212; thirteen, to be exact &amp;#8212; years of preparing myself. If I had started full-time freelancing thirteen years [&amp;hellip;]</description><pubDate>Sun, 07 Feb 2016 22:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>How to negotiate better prices for your design</title><link>https://ayal.github.io/blog/negotiate-better-prices-design/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://ayal.github.io/blog/negotiate-better-prices-design/</guid><description>Every time I would meet a client or ask for a raise or negotiated my salary (when I worked in a full-time position) &amp;#8211; it was a struggle. You see, I was asking for what I thought was an honest number. Didn&amp;#8217;t work so well&amp;#8230; My new video will show you what I learned about [&amp;hellip;]</description><pubDate>Sun, 27 Dec 2015 22:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Selling your digital art  - nuANSWERS</title><link>https://ayal.github.io/blog/nuanswers-sell-digital-art/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://ayal.github.io/blog/nuanswers-sell-digital-art/</guid><description>“nuANSWERS” is where we feature an actual question submitted by one of our students and the answer we gave them. This week’s question comes from Rick, who is looking for tips on how to sell his digital art. Rick wrote: Hi Lior, I purchased the Pricing Class and watched all the videos.  It&amp;#8217;s great and I&amp;#8217;m [&amp;hellip;]</description><pubDate>Tue, 17 Feb 2015 22:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Privacy Notice (GDPR)</title><link>https://ayal.github.io/blog/nublog-privacy-notice/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://ayal.github.io/blog/nublog-privacy-notice/</guid><description>Last updated: 2018/05/23 This notice falls under the&amp;nbsp;General Data Protection Regulation&amp;nbsp;(GDPR). Who we are We&amp;#8217;ve been incorporated in Israel, 2014 How To Contact Us If you have any questions about this Privacy Policy, the practices of this site, or your dealings with this site, please contact us at: The nuSchool www.thenuschool.com 29 Machane Yosef, Tel-Aviv, [&amp;hellip;]</description><pubDate>Wed, 24 May 2017 21:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>How A Freelance Designer Uses An Onboarding Process To Attract Clients</title><link>https://ayal.github.io/blog/onboarding-clients/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://ayal.github.io/blog/onboarding-clients/</guid><description>Post originally published here. Every touch point you have with a client lead is an opportunity to provide them with a remarkable onboarding experience. Based on how you deliver those experiences, it could lead to signed contracts and more exciting work in the future. You’re a creative working with clients. You’re running a clientele business, [&amp;hellip;]</description><pubDate>Sun, 10 Apr 2016 21:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Why Should I Pick YOU?</title><link>https://ayal.github.io/blog/pick/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://ayal.github.io/blog/pick/</guid><description>Most of us think that the only parameter that determines whether or not we win a project, is how much money we ask for it. I think differently. Equally important, is how relevant to the job you – yes, YOU, are. I think we got it all wrong – it’s not “just business”, it’s personal. [&amp;hellip;]</description><pubDate>Wed, 10 Dec 2014 22:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>How To Pick Your Next Sexy Domain Name: A Practical Guide</title><link>https://ayal.github.io/blog/picking-a-sexy-domain-name/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://ayal.github.io/blog/picking-a-sexy-domain-name/</guid><description>Let’s face it, most domain names on the internet are boring. I don’t really know why that is. Maybe it’s because the process of getting a domain is too technical. Or maybe people don’t really like taking time to think of the right name. Either way, this must change… Your next domain name should be [&amp;hellip;]</description><pubDate>Wed, 22 Mar 2017 22:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Pay Me Or Else &amp;#8211; our new free ebook</title><link>https://ayal.github.io/blog/pay-else-new-free-ebook/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://ayal.github.io/blog/pay-else-new-free-ebook/</guid><pubDate>Sun, 12 Apr 2015 21:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Our Manifest</title><link>https://ayal.github.io/blog/our-manifest-the-nuschool-creative-professional/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://ayal.github.io/blog/our-manifest-the-nuschool-creative-professional/</guid><description>So you chose to be a creative professional. You&amp;#8217;ve decided you’re not going to make a living by being a paper pusher, but rather live from your art. Awesome. You wake up in the morning feeling motivated to create beautiful, useful and meaningful things. But then reality bites &amp;#8211; Your accountant is calling, asking you [&amp;hellip;]</description><pubDate>Wed, 17 Sep 2014 21:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Portfolios: Your First Date with A Client</title><link>https://ayal.github.io/blog/portfolios-first-date-client/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://ayal.github.io/blog/portfolios-first-date-client/</guid><description>Spoiler: there&amp;#8217;s a tool to help you build a portfolio within minutes in the end of this post. Don&amp;#8217;t look! Don&amp;#8217;t look! When a potential client lands on your portfolio, it’s a lot like a first-date. It’s the first time this potential client has seen you (and your work). While they browse through your portfolio, [&amp;hellip;]</description><pubDate>Tue, 20 Jan 2015 22:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Planning Your Next Step as a Freelancer</title><link>https://ayal.github.io/blog/planning-next-step-freelancer/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://ayal.github.io/blog/planning-next-step-freelancer/</guid><description>ֹIf you’re lucky, you’ll wake up one morning &amp;#8211; or finish a project, or have a shower moment &amp;#8211; and realize that you’re ready to move into the next phase of your career. More likely, though, is that it won’t be obvious &amp;#8211; because it will be gradual, like having a harder time waking up [&amp;hellip;]</description><pubDate>Wed, 03 Jan 2018 22:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>How to price a logo design: free tools and tips from the pros</title><link>https://ayal.github.io/blog/price-logo-design/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://ayal.github.io/blog/price-logo-design/</guid><description>[This post was updated on July-29 after I got lots of feedback, with more tips. It&amp;#8217;s now even more complete.] So you were asked to give a price quote for producing a new logo, ah? How hard can that be? you ask yourself. I’ll just look it up on the internet, you think. LOL. Asking Google something like [&amp;hellip;]</description><pubDate>Mon, 27 Jul 2015 21:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>How To Price Web Copy</title><link>https://ayal.github.io/blog/price-web-copy/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://ayal.github.io/blog/price-web-copy/</guid><description>The least sexy thing a client can say is, How much will this cost? Pricing is painful. And it&amp;#8217;s not an exact science. I&amp;#8217;ll send you a quote by tomorrow morning, you say, and thus begins the cycle: Googling, asking friends, anonymously posting on Quora, going on Facebook, posting on Twitter, back to Google&amp;#8230; And now [&amp;hellip;]</description><pubDate>Sun, 20 Mar 2016 22:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Being Forced Into Ultimate Productivity (And The Willpower That Comes With)</title><link>https://ayal.github.io/blog/productivity-and-willpower/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://ayal.github.io/blog/productivity-and-willpower/</guid><description>Let&amp;#8217;s talk productivity. Productivity only works when you have the willpower to start moving. No matter how much work piles up, without the burning fiery need to get it done, the productivity engines can&amp;#8217;t get started. Like pita without hummus, or Chandler without Joey, productivity falls flat without willpower. Recently, my wife and her brother [&amp;hellip;]</description><pubDate>Sat, 28 May 2016 21:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Say Goodbye To Uncontrolled Growth In A Project&amp;#8217;s Scope</title><link>https://ayal.github.io/blog/project-scope-endless-changes/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://ayal.github.io/blog/project-scope-endless-changes/</guid><description>Scope creep (also called requirement creep, function creep, feature creep, or kitchen sink syndrome) in project management refers to changes, continuous or uncontrolled growth in a project&amp;#8217;s scope, at any point after the project begins. [Wikipedia] &amp;nbsp; Scope creep is awful. We struggled with how to handle it for years at Paper Leaf. It’s a tricky balance, [&amp;hellip;]</description><pubDate>Tue, 18 Apr 2017 21:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Save Yourself From Endless Client Requests</title><link>https://ayal.github.io/blog/save-endless-client-requests/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://ayal.github.io/blog/save-endless-client-requests/</guid><description>[This post is now updated with even more tips and a slideshow] &amp;#8211; “There’s one more thing I need you to do…” &amp;#8211; “Can we add those last few things to the design before we publish?” &amp;#8211; “I had a dream last night. We need to re-do everything!” There’s nothing I hate more than hearing my clients [&amp;hellip;]</description><pubDate>Tue, 20 May 2014 21:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>SELF-DRIVING CARS ARE THE BEST! AND THE WORST!</title><link>https://ayal.github.io/blog/self-driving-cars-are-the-best-and-the-worst/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://ayal.github.io/blog/self-driving-cars-are-the-best-and-the-worst/</guid><description>I got my driver license on Christmas 96′. Being able to play a CD of the Beatles in my mom’s old Subaru, seemed like a cutting-edge technology back then. Hardly had I known that 18 years later, cars will drive themselves. I spent a lot of time and money on my driving lessons. But hearing …</description><pubDate>Wed, 07 Dec 2016 22:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Self-Promotion For The Introverted Freelancer</title><link>https://ayal.github.io/blog/self-promotion-for-introverts/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://ayal.github.io/blog/self-promotion-for-introverts/</guid><description>Once upon a time, in a magical kingdom, introverted creative freelancers lived and worked in peace. Clients communicated their projects by email once a month, with a mid-month review, and otherwise the kingdom was silent (save for the sound of keyboards and mouse clicks). The citizens were happy and well-fed. Everything was coming up Sketch. [&amp;hellip;]</description><pubDate>Mon, 27 Jun 2016 21:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Setting Boundaries Like a Boss</title><link>https://ayal.github.io/blog/setting-boundaries-and-managing-time-like-a-boss-because-you-are-the-boss/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://ayal.github.io/blog/setting-boundaries-and-managing-time-like-a-boss-because-you-are-the-boss/</guid><description>It&amp;#8217;s a Friday evening at 7:00 pm. My laptop is shut, and I&amp;#8217;m done for the day. I&amp;#8217;m ready to go out and have dinner with some friends and just one glass of totally-fine-for-my-waistline wine (or three, but who&amp;#8217;s counting). And then it happens: the dreaded client email. &amp;#8220;Hey, can you fix this one thing [&amp;hellip;]</description><pubDate>Tue, 25 Aug 2015 21:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Start Here</title><link>https://ayal.github.io/blog/start-here-nuschool/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://ayal.github.io/blog/start-here-nuschool/</guid><description>[Scroll to the goodies] Are you a creative freelancer? Start here&amp;#8230; We see creative people all around us living great lives: having a good work-life balance, making good money, working with great clients and creating amazing stuff. Do you think those people are more talented than you? Or have more luck? Probably not. Here’s an [&amp;hellip;]</description><pubDate>Mon, 25 May 2015 21:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>How to Stay Productive as a Remote Worker (Without Missing Out on Traveling)</title><link>https://ayal.github.io/blog/stay-productive-remote-worker/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://ayal.github.io/blog/stay-productive-remote-worker/</guid><description>Most posts about productivity as a remote worker read like a how-to on turning your home into a cubicle: keep business hours, dress for work, create a &amp;#8220;work area.&amp;#8221; I take issue with advice like this, because it seems to point to the idea that the only way you can be as productive from home [&amp;hellip;]</description><pubDate>Sun, 05 Apr 2015 21:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>How to Tell Your Client They&amp;#8217;re Wrong Without Getting Fired</title><link>https://ayal.github.io/blog/tell-your-client-they-are-wrong-without-getting-fired/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://ayal.github.io/blog/tell-your-client-they-are-wrong-without-getting-fired/</guid><description>You&amp;#8217;re on the phone, head in your hands. It&amp;#8217;s been 20 minutes and your client is still talking about the first ad that you sent over. You know it&amp;#8217;s good. And they said they like it, but then they say something to the effect of I&amp;#8217;m just not sure. Or the inevitable, Can we make [&amp;hellip;]</description><pubDate>Tue, 03 Nov 2015 22:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Thankful For The Women Before Me</title><link>https://ayal.github.io/blog/thankful-for-the-women-before-me/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://ayal.github.io/blog/thankful-for-the-women-before-me/</guid><description>There’s much work to do when it comes to equality between the genders in the workplace. However, I like to think about how far we’ve come, especially during this time of year when we tend to reflect on what we’re grateful for. Working women before us had so many barriers to overcome and thanks to a [&amp;hellip;]</description><pubDate>Sun, 22 Nov 2015 22:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>THE BARISTA WHO DIDN&amp;#8217;T GIVE A FUCK</title><link>https://ayal.github.io/blog/the-barista-who-didnt-give-a-fuck/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://ayal.github.io/blog/the-barista-who-didnt-give-a-fuck/</guid><description>Creativity. We had it before we lost it.</description><pubDate>Mon, 22 Aug 2016 21:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>THE EASIER WAY TO BE EXTRAORDINARY</title><link>https://ayal.github.io/blog/the-easier-way-to-be-extraordinary/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://ayal.github.io/blog/the-easier-way-to-be-extraordinary/</guid><description>To be extraordinary?!  Now that’s a big promise, Lior! Yes it is, I know. I’m not here to waste your time after all. EXTRAORINAIRE I love the word “extraordinary”. It’s an extraordinary word. It’s much better than “pompous”, “great” or “enormous” – because it gives you a h&amp;#8230;</description><pubDate>Wed, 31 May 2017 21:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>The Reasons You&amp;#8217;re Losing Design Contracts</title><link>https://ayal.github.io/blog/the-donts-of-writing-a-winning-proposal/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://ayal.github.io/blog/the-donts-of-writing-a-winning-proposal/</guid><description>Editor’s note: This guest post is written by Jeff Archibald. He is co-founder of a design agency in Edmonton called Paper Leaf, an award-winning shop focused on brand identities, websites, and interfaces. If he&amp;#8217;s not learning, creating, speaking or herding cats, he&amp;#8217;s partaking in one of his many other loves: coffee, typography, whisky, cycling and the mountains. [&amp;hellip;]</description><pubDate>Sun, 19 Oct 2014 21:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Planning For The Unplanned Emergency (The Freelance Way)</title><link>https://ayal.github.io/blog/the-emergency-survival-manual/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://ayal.github.io/blog/the-emergency-survival-manual/</guid><description>A few months ago, after a night of stomach cramps, I woke up in excruciating, doubled-over-can’t-breathe pain. Terrified and alone, I hopped a cab to the ER, from where I was admitted to the hospital with kidney stones. Fuck. It was the middle of the week, and I was out for the count. No computer, [&amp;hellip;]</description><pubDate>Sun, 19 Jun 2016 21:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>The 20-Step Checklist For Getting Your First Clients</title><link>https://ayal.github.io/blog/the-freelancers-guide-to-clients/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://ayal.github.io/blog/the-freelancers-guide-to-clients/</guid><description>So, you’re looking to get more clients &amp;#8212; or even more exciting, your first clients. Welcome to the club! Today is the first day of the rest of your career. Let that sink in for a second. Do you feel that tingling in your stomach? That’s excitement. Today’s going to be a good day. Here&amp;#8217;s [&amp;hellip;]</description><pubDate>Mon, 14 Mar 2016 22:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Freelancers, Listen Up: The Gig Economy Isn&apos;t For You</title><link>https://ayal.github.io/blog/the-gig-economy/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://ayal.github.io/blog/the-gig-economy/</guid><description>We live in changing times. Since 2013, when Carl Benedikt predicted that 47% of the jobs that exist today will be automated and taken over by robots (!), there&amp;#8217;s been mass media panic about where we&amp;#8217;ll be when the jobpocalypse hits. In an attempt to protect humankind and preserve capitalism, one response to this fear has been [&amp;hellip;]</description><pubDate>Mon, 07 Nov 2016 22:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>The Stability Myth</title><link>https://ayal.github.io/blog/the-stability-myth/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://ayal.github.io/blog/the-stability-myth/</guid><description>Chances are, someone&amp;#8217;s tried to talk you out of freelancing. Whether it&amp;#8217;s your concerned mom or your significant other who reeeaalllly needs you to help out with the rent, freelancers aren&amp;#8217;t known for their income stability &amp;#8211; especially freelance creatives. We even joke about it ourselves. End of the month ramen parties, amiright? And as [&amp;hellip;]</description><pubDate>Mon, 05 Sep 2016 21:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>The Worst Project Proposal In History (Case-Study)</title><link>https://ayal.github.io/blog/the-worst-project-proposal-in-history-case-study/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://ayal.github.io/blog/the-worst-project-proposal-in-history-case-study/</guid><description>I&amp;#8217;m going to tell you about the worst project proposal ever written by yours truly. By the end of this post, you&amp;#8217;ll know exactly what NOT to do when writing proposals &amp;#8211; saving yourself a large amount of time and money. But first &amp;#8211; let me ask you this: do you remember your first kiss? I’ll remember mine [&amp;hellip;]</description><pubDate>Sat, 30 May 2015 21:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Things I’ve learned as a freelance designer</title><link>https://ayal.github.io/blog/things-i-learned-as-a-freelance-designer/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://ayal.github.io/blog/things-i-learned-as-a-freelance-designer/</guid><description>You wouldn&amp;#8217;t see the &amp;#8220;freelancer&amp;#8221; title in my LinkedIn profile. But the truth is, I work as one since I was 17. I had my first paid project while I’m still in high school. It was a 3D design project of the Hebrew Temple of the Egyptian era. Then came an opportunity to do a freelance [&amp;hellip;]</description><pubDate>Sun, 08 Nov 2015 22:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Three principles your contract must align with</title><link>https://ayal.github.io/blog/three-principles-your-contract-must-align-with/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://ayal.github.io/blog/three-principles-your-contract-must-align-with/</guid><description>Being a freelancer is awesome. You are the boss, you manage your time, your projects, your mid-day naps (don’t worry, we won’t tell anyone about your naps. nuSchoolers believe that napping is great ). As a freelancer, you don’t share your profits with anyone but yourself. Well, maybe with your dog in case you got one. On [&amp;hellip;]</description><pubDate>Tue, 26 Aug 2014 21:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>The Tools Freelance Designers Need</title><link>https://ayal.github.io/blog/tools-freelance-designers-need/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://ayal.github.io/blog/tools-freelance-designers-need/</guid><description>If you’re starting your Google search with “best…,” you’re already in trouble. We know the struggle to find the easiest/friendliest/cheapest accounting software, font stores, time management tools, and whatever else you need &amp;#8212; so we put together a list of resources, what we use as a team and alone to keep our brains and careers [&amp;hellip;]</description><pubDate>Wed, 06 Jan 2016 22:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Educating Your Clients</title><link>https://ayal.github.io/blog/uneducated-client-unhappy-client/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://ayal.github.io/blog/uneducated-client-unhappy-client/</guid><description>It started with a lot of compliments.  My mom&amp;#8217;s friend hired me to help rebrand her eCommerce business. She told me how much she loved my vibe, how impressed she was with my knowledge of her market, and how much she enjoyed my writing. With a background in journalism, my client, L, openly admitted to [&amp;hellip;]</description><pubDate>Mon, 25 Jul 2016 21:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Awesome pricing technique for writing design proposals</title><link>https://ayal.github.io/blog/what-i-learned-about-pricing-while-being-stuck-in-traffic/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://ayal.github.io/blog/what-i-learned-about-pricing-while-being-stuck-in-traffic/</guid><description>Can you believe that a single pricing technique has changed how much I earn? Not only that, but it made my clients happy as well. Unbelievable. Until a few years ago, I used to drive 45 minutes to work every day. I would listen to Audiobooks in my car while being stuck in traffic. Between Spanish lessons, Cooking podcasts and Medieval History, I [&amp;hellip;]</description><pubDate>Thu, 09 Oct 2014 21:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>What I Learned From 60 Rejections From Design Studios</title><link>https://ayal.github.io/blog/what-i-learned-from-60-rejections-from-design-studios/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://ayal.github.io/blog/what-i-learned-from-60-rejections-from-design-studios/</guid><description>Rejection sucks. Especially lots of rejection. Whether it&amp;#8217;s work, love, or wherever else, rejection means you put yourself out there &amp;#8212; and someone said, no thanks, I&amp;#8217;d rather not. There&amp;#8217;s no quicker way to make a person doubt their skills than to reject them. And it happened to me 60 times. For designers, internships are a [&amp;hellip;]</description><pubDate>Sun, 24 Apr 2016 21:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Designer&apos;s life hacks by Aaron Draplin, Gemma O’Brien and more (VIDEO)</title><link>https://ayal.github.io/blog/typo-2015/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://ayal.github.io/blog/typo-2015/</guid><description>Learning from people who are smarter than you, is the sure way to become a better designer (and a better person). That&amp;#8217;s exactly the reason why I took the time to fly to Berlin and attend the TYPO 2015 conference. I&amp;#8217;ve had the pleasure to talk with the top speakers who are some of the [&amp;hellip;]</description><pubDate>Wed, 03 Jun 2015 21:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>UPGRADE ME, SCOTTY</title><link>https://ayal.github.io/blog/upgrade-me-up-scotty/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://ayal.github.io/blog/upgrade-me-up-scotty/</guid><description>I’m addicted to TV shows that describe the horrible world we’re living in. Westworld, Mr. Robot, Black Mirror … There are plenty of dystopias these days, with intriguing scripts, and great plots. Watching the world goes to hell gives me pleasure.  The shows explain that it’s a horrific worl&amp;#8230;</description><pubDate>Fri, 07 Oct 2016 21:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>When And How To Say No To A Project</title><link>https://ayal.github.io/blog/when-and-how-to-say-no-to-a-project/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://ayal.github.io/blog/when-and-how-to-say-no-to-a-project/</guid><description>&amp;#8220;Uhhh&amp;#8230;. I don&amp;#8217;t think I can&amp;#8230;?&amp;#8221; I quickly look side to side like a shifty villain. &amp;#8220;Sorry, but I can&amp;#8217;t.&amp;#8221; I hang my head and do a half grin. &amp;#8220;I&amp;#8217;m sorry, but no.&amp;#8221; I smile a big flashy smile, maybe that&amp;#8217;ll soften the blow. &amp;#8220;No.&amp;#8221; I start sweating. I sweat when I&amp;#8217;m nervous, okay?! Welcome [&amp;hellip;]</description><pubDate>Mon, 28 Sep 2015 21:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>WHEN LIFE GIVES BEYONCE A CHEATING JAY-Z, SHE MAKES LEMONADE</title><link>https://ayal.github.io/blog/when-life-gives-beyonce-a-cheating-jay-z-she-makes-lemonade/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://ayal.github.io/blog/when-life-gives-beyonce-a-cheating-jay-z-she-makes-lemonade/</guid><description>And so Jay Z was cheating on Beyoncé and I get to write a post about marketing?!</description><pubDate>Fri, 07 Oct 2016 21:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>WHO HAS THE UPPER HAND IN YOUR CAREER?</title><link>https://ayal.github.io/blog/who-has-the-upper-hand-in-your-career/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://ayal.github.io/blog/who-has-the-upper-hand-in-your-career/</guid><description>Never ask me for a relationship advice. I mean, I’m happily married to a girl I love, but I don’t think I figured it out. I feel I have no clue how this whole “love” thingy works.  Well… maybe there’s one thing I DO know about relationships. It’s more about&amp;#8230;</description><pubDate>Wed, 07 Sep 2016 21:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Who’s afraid of a $50 logo?</title><link>https://ayal.github.io/blog/whos-afraid-cheap-logos/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://ayal.github.io/blog/whos-afraid-cheap-logos/</guid><description>If there’s one thing that scares us even more than the prospect of cheaper competitors learning to design and offering it at a cheap price, it’s that someone in Silicon Valley will open a startup that can automate design &amp;#8211; thus putting the last nail in our coffin. When companies like 99 Designs &amp;amp; Fiverr offered super cheap [&amp;hellip;]</description><pubDate>Sun, 08 Mar 2015 22:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Who’s responsible for setting up a website hosting for my client? nuAnswers</title><link>https://ayal.github.io/blog/whos-responsible-setting-website-hosting-client-nuanswers/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://ayal.github.io/blog/whos-responsible-setting-website-hosting-client-nuanswers/</guid><description>“nuANSWERS” is where we feature an actual question submitted by one of our students and the answer we gave them. This week’s question comes from Fern, who wants to know how involved you should be in setting up a website hosting for your client Fern wrote: Lior, Thank you for writing an excellent, straight forward article [&amp;hellip;]</description><pubDate>Mon, 02 Mar 2015 22:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Why clients are not lining up at your doorstep</title><link>https://ayal.github.io/blog/why-clients-are-not-lining-up-at-your-doorstep/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://ayal.github.io/blog/why-clients-are-not-lining-up-at-your-doorstep/</guid><description>The truth is not always fun to hear. If you are one of those people who have a hard time facing the truth, you might want to stop reading right now. Not everyone is looking to hear the truth about themselves. I found that out when I was in design school: I thought I was [&amp;hellip;]</description><pubDate>Tue, 01 Sep 2015 21:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Working on Weekends</title><link>https://ayal.github.io/blog/working-freelance-on-weekends/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://ayal.github.io/blog/working-freelance-on-weekends/</guid><description>If you’re a freelancer, it’s easy to fall into the trap. For me, working all the time made me tired of what I love the most. I’ve been working freelance since 2004 (2007 full-time I guess). During this time, I alternated periods of intense work (when I ran out of money) with a very relaxed work [&amp;hellip;]</description><pubDate>Wed, 11 Feb 2015 22:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Freelancers: Why you need a contract for every project</title><link>https://ayal.github.io/blog/why-you-need-a-contract-for-every-project/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://ayal.github.io/blog/why-you-need-a-contract-for-every-project/</guid><description>Are you starting a new client project soon? Stop what you’re doing right now and go make a contract for that project before you do anything else. As a designer, it can be easy to jump past the initial stages of a client project and get right to designing. Usually, you’re excited about getting to [&amp;hellip;]</description><pubDate>Sun, 03 May 2015 21:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Creative, Win More Clients &amp;#8211; 14 Proven Ways</title><link>https://ayal.github.io/blog/win-more-creative-clients-kyle-courtright/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://ayal.github.io/blog/win-more-creative-clients-kyle-courtright/</guid><description>If you can’t win clients, you don’t have a business. End of story. Once a prospect inquires, how do you show them that you are the answer? How do you differentiate from the five other creatives they reached out to? I want to help you stand out in a sea of competition. Over the years, having the opportunity to work with [&amp;hellip;]</description><pubDate>Mon, 23 Jan 2017 22:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Writing Tips for Designers</title><link>https://ayal.github.io/blog/writing-designers/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://ayal.github.io/blog/writing-designers/</guid><description>Writing is an inevitable part of a designer’s day-to-day: preparing work proposals, composing lengthy official emails, creating copy for designs. Even though you first set out to develop a career in a visual field, soon enough you will discover that using that particular brain function is not enough, and will be forced to go literal [&amp;hellip;]</description><pubDate>Sun, 19 Apr 2015 21:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>You should be napping &amp;#8211; Yeah!</title><link>https://ayal.github.io/blog/you-should-be-napping-yeah/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://ayal.github.io/blog/you-should-be-napping-yeah/</guid><description>You should be napping. It can improve your energy level, productivity, memory and happiness. C&amp;#8217;mon, I know you think I&amp;#8217;m just looking for excuses to sleep in the middle of the day, but this is scientific. Seriously. Winston Churchill needed it for winning wars &amp;#8211; he was the one who coined the term &amp;#8220;power-nap&amp;#8221;. Bill Clinton, Margaret Thatcher, Albert [&amp;hellip;]</description><pubDate>Sun, 12 Oct 2014 21:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Your Free Design Work Will End Up In The Trash</title><link>https://ayal.github.io/blog/your-free-design-work-will-end-up-in-the-trash/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://ayal.github.io/blog/your-free-design-work-will-end-up-in-the-trash/</guid><description>I lost $100,000, and that&amp;#8217;s just a rough estimate. If only I hadn’t worked for free for so many years, who knows, maybe I could have owned my own apartment by now. I thought it would be good for my career, bring opportunities, help my friends, my family, that it would help me make a political [&amp;hellip;]</description><pubDate>Mon, 10 Nov 2014 22:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>YOU&amp;#8217;RE AT A CROSSROAD. NOW WHAT?</title><link>https://ayal.github.io/blog/youre-at-a-crossroad-now-what/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://ayal.github.io/blog/youre-at-a-crossroad-now-what/</guid><description>[This is an open letter written to someone who asked me what I think about crossroads in your career and options and how to choose between them]. You’re at a crossroad. You know how you got here, but not sure where you’re headed. And it’s confusing. One way seems smooth and easy – but maybe &amp;#8230;</description><pubDate>Tue, 07 Mar 2017 22:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>